Finding Aid for Homer Ferguson Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Photographs
  - Philippines Ambassadorship
    - Garcia, Paulino J. (Philippine Secretary of Health) (Box 24)
    - Groups: Identified (Box 24)
    - Groups: Unidentified, 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Hoover Jr., Herbert: Visit (Box 24)
    - Italy, Minister of: Decoration by Secretary of National Defense (Box 24)
    - Luncheon (occasion unknown) (Box 24)
    - Magnaya Visit (Box 24)
    - Media Photographers (Box 24)
      (photograph of Ferguson with Evening News and Manila Chronicle photographers)
    - Military Base Tours and Inspections (Box 24)
    - Nangka PRRM Project Inspection, June 12, 1955 (Box 24)
    - Negros Oriental (see Dumaguette) (Box 24)
    - Official Calls (Box 24)
    - Republic of Indonesia: Tenth Anniversary of the Proclamation of Independence (Box 24)
    - Return Visit, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor: Visit (Box 24)
    - Swearing In Ceremony, and Presentation of Credentials (Box 24)
      (includes pictures of the Fergusons departing for the Far East)
    - Veterans Memorial Hospital: Inspection (Box 24)
    - Visiting Dignitaries and Prominent Individuals (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - United States Court Of Military Appeals
    - Activities, 3 folders (Box 24)
      (includes pictures with Gerald Ford and Dwight Eisenhower)
    - Banquets/Receptions (Box 24)
    - Brucker, Wilbur M. (Box 24)
    - Groups: Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Members of the Court (Box 24)
      (see also Activities)
    - Michigan Delegation Breakfast, 1961 (Box 24)
    - Military Installation Visits (Box 24)
    - Retirement Ceremony (Box 24)
      (negatives for most of these photos-see Negatives)
    - United States Navy: acquaintances and activities (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
  - Inter-Parliamentary Union
    - Iran, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Israel, 1960s (Box 24)
    - Japan and Korea, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Kennedy Space Center Tour, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Paris, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Peru and Colombia, 1968 (Box 24)
    - Washington, D.C., 1953 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Dates Unknown (probably primarily from Senate years)
    - Liquor Control Commission (Box 24)
      (line outside retail store, circa 1940s)
    - Plant Tours (Box 24)
    - Prominent Individuals (Box 24)
      (includes: Herbert Hoover; Joan Crawford; Gerald Ford; Willy Brandt; Harry Truman; William Rogers; Wilbur Brucker; Herbert Hoover; and King Hussein of Jordan)
    - Public Appearances (Box 24)
    - Racist Photography (Box 24)
    - Travel
      - Far East (includes pictures of Ferguson with hospitalized soldiers) (Box 24)
      - Italy (a book of photographs of Rome) (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 24)
      (see also negatives)
  - Negatives (Box 24)
    (Include Myrtle Ferguson Portraits; U.S. Court of Military Appeals, Retirement Ceremony; Date Unknown, Miscellaneous)
  - Film
    - Date and Subject unknown, 8 film reels (8mm) (Box 24)
  - Albums
    - "Inspection of Army and Navy Installations, Alaska and Aleutian Islands, August 28, 1943-September 14, 1943" by the Special Committee to Investigate the National Defense Program, U.S. Senate (Box 25)
    - Pearl Harbor Committee and other subjects, 1942-1944 (Box 25)
    - "Investigation of Panama and Caribbean Sea Defenses." U.S. Senate Committee to investigate the National Defense March 25-April 4, 1945. Honorable Julius K. Amberg, Special Assistant to the Secretary of War, author and editor. (Box 25)
      (Includes Miami, Florida; Cuba; Puerto Rico; Antigua, Guadeloupe; Dominica; Windward Islands; Trinidad, Curacao and Aruba)
    - "The Subcommittee of the Special Senate Committee Investigating the National Defense Program in the European and Mediterranean Theaters of Operations, May 17-June 9, 1945." (Box 25)
    - Visit of Harry S. Truman, President of the United States, to the Infantry Center, Fort Benning, Georgia, April 21, 1950 (Box 25)
    - Album from the Philippines period, Assembled by Chief Photographer Felix Manuel at Malacañang, 1955-1956; Small 8 x 10 volume bound in green and black plastic (Box 25)
    - Album from the Philippines period assembled by Chief Photographer Felix Manuel at Malacañang, 1955-1956; large, 10 x 14 volume bound in green and black plastic (Box 25)
    - "A Visit to the Armor Combat Training Center, Camp Irwin, California, by the Honorable Wilbur M. Brucker ", May 23, 1958 (Box 25)
      (Stamped in gold on cover: Judge Homer Ferguson)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings series consists of a reel-to reel tape of a 1967 speech, some Eidison Voicewriter discs of memos and other materials from the period when he was a member of the U.S. Court of Military Appeals, and phonograph records of statements taken for the One-Man Grand Jury, 1939-1941.
  - Statements taken for Wayne County graft grand jury, 1939-1941; 35 phonograph records (in carrying case) (Box 25)
    (located separately)
  - Edison Voicewriter discs of memos, letters, conference notes, miscellaneous, mostly from the late, 1950s (Box 25)
    (recording speed unknown)
  - Address Ferguson gave in the Philippines in honor of Rizal Day, 1967 January 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 25)
    - [Part 1], [85187-SR-1-1]; (Ferguson commemorates José Rizal, Filipino nationalist and leader.)
  - "Rizal Day Address", 1967; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 25)
- Myrtle Ferguson Papers, 1946-1966; 1 linear foot
  The Myrtle Ferguson Papers series (1946-1966; 1 linear ft.) is somewhat limited in nature. Her correspondence is organized by year and is, for the most part, routine. The researcher will find, however, interesting reflections on her 1953 trips through Michigan with her husband, and on her husband's 1954 election defeat. There are files of materials on the "Washington News Letter," published by the National Federation of Women's Republican Clubs, the editorial staff of which included Mrs. Ferguson. Issues exist for the years 1949-1952, although only scattered issues are available for the latter year. In addition, there are copies of the syndicated column Mrs. Ferguson wrote while in Washington, D.C., "Washington Notes and Notables." It does not appear, however, that there is a complete run of the columns.
  - Biographical, 2 folders (Box 26)
    (mostly materials regarding social organizations/causes)
  - Correspondence, undated; 1946-1966; 5 folders (Box 26)
  - "Washington News Letter"
    - Correspondence (Box 26)
    - Drafts (Box 26)
    - Issues (Box 26)
  - "Washington Notes and Notables" (Box 26)